A Guide to the Weaver-Brady Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #38-98
Weaver-Brady Papers 1824-1878
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
38-98
ca. 1500 item and 79 volumes
Douglas E. Brady
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Weaver-Brady Papers were acquired in 3 groups over a period of 6 years. Douglas E. Brady deposited the initial batch (38-98) in 1938. Nos. 1590 & 1993 were purchased in 1943 & 1944. As the 3 groups complimented each other it was decided to interfile them.
Scope and Content
Spanning the years 1824-1878, the Weaver-Brady Papers comprise ca. 1,500 items and 79 bound volumes. These are the business papers of William Weaver(1780-1863) ironmaster and pioneer in scientific agriculture. Correspondence, bills and receipts, legal papers, ledgers, daybooks, journals, timebooks, records of free and slave labor, provision account books, cash books and farm and dairy journals concern Weaver's mines, furnaces and forges in Rockbridge, Rockingham and Botetourt Cos., grist mills in Rockingham Co., corn production experiments, beef and hide dealings, and land sales. The names of his operations are as follows: Bath Iron Works, Buffalo Forge, Emma Mines, Etna Furnace, Liberty Furnace, Lydia Furnace, Potosi Mine and Spring Mills.
An index to correspondents and recipients has been prepared with the letters being listed individually. The phrase "(In non correspondence)-indicates that other items (bills, receipts, loose accounts and legal papers) appear through out the collection, except in the folders labeled "Letters". It is realized that this method creates confusion in locating specific items. However, the sheer bulk of receipts, etc. prohibits an individual listing.
Additional Information
Index to Correspondents and Recipients
Albright, Joseph I. (In non correspondence -legal)
Albright Sherrerd & Co. (In non correspondence -legal)
Allen, Brown M., d. 1883 (1881 Jan. 5, ALS, to W.A. Anderson, re: sale of Hoffman lands) (1881 Jan. 17, ALS, to [W.W.], re: sale of land)
Alphin, William (1859 Aug. 19, ALS, to [W.W.], re: 300 bu. corn) (In non correspondence)
Ambler, James M. (1891 Mar. 12, ALS, C.C. Jones to Ambler, re: David Hoffman's tax bills)
Anderson, Francis Thomas, 1808 -1887 (1856 July 7, ALS to J.D. Davidson, re: need of water for his blast furnace) (1857 July 17, ALS, to Alfred Dugless, re: economic and legal affairs) (1862 June 2, ALS, to W.W., re: urgent request for an iron order) (1862 June 20, ALS, to W.W., re: angry letter about a mistake of Weaver's)
Anderson (R.B.) & Co. (In non correspondence -receipt)
Anderson, William Alexander, 1842-1930 (1881 Jan. 5, ALS, B.M. Allen to Anderson, re: sale of land) (1891 Mar. 27, ALS, H.E. Talbott to Anderson, re: meeting with Anderson)
Armistead, William ([1829], ALS, to W. W., re: plate for a shovel plough) (In non correspondence -bills and receipts)
Ayres, David E. (1859 May 19, ALC, to Brady, re: payment of 75 cents) (In non correspondence -receipts)
Ayers, M. P. (1859 May 2, ALS, to W.W., re: order for 4 tires)
Ayres, William L. (1856 Jan. 13, ALS, to W.W., re: payment of debt owed) (1856 Mar. 10, ALS, to J.D. Davidson, re: payment of debts) (1859 May 70, ALS, to W.W., re: 5 bu. corn) (1862, Feb. 1, ALS, to W.W., re: promise to pay debt)
Bach & Bros. (In non correspondence)
Bacon and Lewis, Lexington (1861 Apr. 8, ALS, to W.W., re: inquiry into what to do with unsold flour)
Bagby, George (1851 July 4, ALS, from William Lakford, re: dissolution of partnership of Martin and Better)
Baker, John (In non correspondence -accounts and receipts)
Barton, Randolph (1891, ALS, C.C. Jones to Barton and Geo. A. VanLingen, re: bill)
Bath Forge (1849-52, cash book, 2 vols.)
Baxter, S. S. (1830 Apr. 22, ALS, to W.W., re: bail)
Bell, John, 1797-1869 (1833 May 29, ALS, to W.W, re: machine ordered)
Bowles, P. C. (In non correspondence)
Boyd, Andrew L. (1862 Sept. 23, ALS, to W.W., re: iron order)
Boyd (James) & Co., Lynchburg (1859 Sept. 20, ALS, to W.W., re: metal order)
Boyd, William W. (1851 Feb.16, ALS, to J.D. Davidson, re: purchase of Etna furnace) (1859 Aug. 12, ALS, to W.W., re: negotiations for iron pricing) (In non correspondence -legal and financial) (1859 Aug. 11, ALS, to W.W., re: iron order)
Brady, Daniel E. C. (1859 Aug. 5, ALS, to J.D. Davidson, re: Will's absence) (1861 Apr. 16, ALS, to W.W., re: business affairs) (In non correspondence)
Brooks, John (1861 Mar. 9, ALS, to W.W., re: bond) (In non correspondence -receipts)
Brown, Mrs. E. (In non correspondence)
Brown, Sam H. (In non correspondence)
Brown, William [W.] (In non correspondence)
Bryan, Lafayette O. (1855 Sept. 17, ALS, to J.D. Davidson, re: Bryan's father's debts)
Bryan (M.M.) & Co., Roaches Island (1858 June 30, ALS, to Greenlee Davidson, re: settlement of some debt)
Buchanan, Stuart and Co., Saltville, Va. (1862 Dec. 19, ALS, to W.W. re: exchange of salt and iron)
[Buck] & Bro., Roaring Run (1861 June 7, ALS, to Brady, re: iron order)
Bullock, C. K., Philadelphia (1879 Apr. 5, ALS, to Brady, re: payment of bill)
Bumett, S. H. (1862, Oct. 20, ALS, to W.W., re: iron order)
Byan, M. M. (1855 Oct. 29 ALS, to J.D. Davidson, re: asking price of W.W.'s farm)
Camden, David (In non correspondence)
Camden, Jesse (1859 Apr. 20, ALS, to Brady, re: payment to Sunders) (In non correspondence -receipts)
Camden, Zacari[ah] (In non correspondence)
Camden, Zack R. (In non correspondence)
Campbell, James, 1812-1893 (1828 Jan. 15, ALS, to W.W., re: offer of sale of five or six hundred bushels of grain) (1829 Feb. 21, ALS, to W. W., re: sale of house to John Cummings) (1829 Nov. 25, ALS, to W.W., re: personal news) (1830 Aug. 23, ALS, to Ab. W. Davis, re: delivery of iron to Charlottesville and Richmond)
Carlton Chamberlain and Co., Richmond, Va. (1861 Jan. 23, ALS, to W.W., re: bill for iron ordered)
Carson, J. E. (1859 July 25, ALS, to W. W., re: pick-up of a slave)
Caruthers, John P. (In non correspondence)
Caruthers and Alexander, Lexington, Va. (1829 Jan. 8, ALS, to W.W., re: trade between C & A and W. W.)
Cazenove (A.C.) and Co., Alexandria, Va. (1829 Aug. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: receipt for madeira wine)
Chandler, Samuel [T.] (1859 July 17, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order 2nd credit to acct.) (1859 July 22, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1859 Aug. 25, ALS, to W. W., re: 2 pts. for cast iron) (In non correspondence)
Chapin, C. (In non correspondence -legal)
Chiles, Sylvestus (In non correspondence -statements)
Christian (John B. and; G.), Greenville (1829 Mar. 4, ALS, to W. W., re: wagons)
Clarkes, William (1829 Nov. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: accounts in the suit of W. W. )
Coleman, Robert L. (1857 Nov. 4, ALS, to W. W., re: employment of hands for iron foundary)
Conrad, John (1829 Apr. 1, ALS, to W. W., re: settlement of debt)
Couche, (William D) & Co., Waskey's Mills (1859 July 14, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1859 Aug. 31, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (In non correspondence -receipt)
Crockett, R. H. (1859 Sept. 23, ALS, to W. W., re: letter from Mr. Crouse, cattle freight charges) (1859 Nov. 18, ALS, to W. W., re: cattle market)
[Croun], John (1859 Sept. 17, ALS, to W W., re: sale of iron) (1859 Oct. 14, ALS, to W. W., re: payment of note for $1346.29)
Crump & Ligaz (In non correspondence -receipts)
Crutchfield, Robert (1829 Mar. 30, ALS, to W. W., re: request to answer former letter)
Cumings and Shields (1831 May 12, ALS, to A. Davis, re: transport of iron to Richmond) (In non correspondence -receipts)
Danenhower, James W. (1828 Aug. 6, ALS, to W. W., re: order for one carryale tire) (1829 Oct. 13, ALS, to John Whitmore, re: grinding of 20 bushels of corn and 20 bushels of rye) (In non correspondence -receipts)
[Daturk], William A. (1829 Nov. 2. ALS. to Wm. W. Hughes. re: Hughes' debt to Daturk)
Daulleal, William H. (1824 Nov. 5, ALS, to W. W., re: debt owed)
Davidson, Greenlee (1858 June 30, ALS, M.M. Bryan and Co. to Davidson, re: payment of some debts) (1859 Jan. 16, ALS, to Pa, re: case of Stratton v. Jordan) (1859 July 20, ALS, to W. W., re: discounting of F.B. Dean's note) (1860 Nov. 6, ALS, Vincent Turpin to Davidson, re: Joseph Reed's note to W.W.) (1862 Jan. 16, ALS, to W. W., re: offer to sell Bath Iron Works for $12,000) (1862 Feb. 1, ALS, to W. W., re: status of the ore banks at Bath Forge)
Davidson, James Dorman, 1808-1882 (1839 May 25, ALS, D.J. Wilson to Davidson, re: Maybury-Weaver suit) (1840 Feb. 20, ALS, W.W. to Davidson, re: crops from 1825-30, Mr. Barker) (1840 Sept. 5, ALS, Wm. Moffit to Davidson, re: debt of Jordan and Davis) (1841 Apr. 17, ALS, W.W. to Davidson, re: suit of Baldwin) (1841 Mar. 12, ALS, to W. W., re: acct. which caused suit between Weaver and White) (1848 July 23, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: unidentifiable legal business) (1849 Feb. 1, ALS, S. Sherrerd to Davidson, re: statement of metal delivered) (1849 Nov. 1, ALS, J. Doyle to Davidson, re: operation of furnace) (1849 Nov. 1, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: orders for Davidson) (1849 Nov. 12, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: statement of Sherrerd for 1849) (1851 Feb. 16, ALS, Wm. W. Boyd to Davidson, re: purchase of Etna furnace) (1851 Dec. 19, ALS, J.T. Lain to Davidson, re: purchase of Hite farms) (1852 Jan. 10, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: bond, Baldwin case) (1852 Feb. 7, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: relations with C. Jordan) (1852 July l3, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: sale of slave) (1852 Aug. 11, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: report of the Baldwin case) (1852 Sept. 4, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: agricultural products) (1853 Aug. 16, AlS, M. Bryan to Davidson, re: papers relative to some unidentified land) (1854 [Jan. 4], ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: business with Mr. Barclay) (1854 May 1, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: takeover of some unidentified property) (1854 May 21, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: payment of Barclay for land) (1854 Nov. 10, I.C.C. Moore to Davidson, re: four sacks of salt) (1855 Jan. 31, ALS, to E. N. Davis, re: Greenlee Estate) (1855 Apr. 16, ALS, Jn. Newton to Davidson, re: sale of the land of E. Bujon) (1855 Apr. 16, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: payment of $300.00) (1855 July 12, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: a note for $284.75) (1855 July 14, ALS, McCorkle, Simpson & Jones to Davidson, re: balance due by Bryan & Randolph to Davidson) (1855 Sept. 1, ALS, Hannah [Grimke] to Davidson, re: sale of slave) (1855 Sept. 17, ALS, Lafayette O. Bryan to Davidson, re: Bryan's father's debts) (1855 Sept., ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: Camden's residence) (1855 Oct. 5, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: meeting of William Davidson) (1855 Oct. 22, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: W. W. going to Richmond) (1855 Oct. 29, M. M. Byan to Davidson, re: asking price of W. W.'s farm) (1856 Feb. 2, ALS, Jas. A. F. Randolph to Davidson, re: acct. due Bryan and Randolph) (1856 Mar. 5, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: W. W.'s birthday party) (1856 Mar. 10, ALS, Wm. L. Ayres to Davidson, re: payment of debts) (1856 Apr. 8, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: invitation) (1856 May 10, ALS, Wm. M. McCutchan to Davidson, re: purchase of Weaver's land) (1856 May 18, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: Murry's affairs) (1856 June 20, ALS, H.D. Whitcomb to Davidson, re: Weaver's land at Panther Gap) (1856 July 7, ALS, F.T. Anderson to Davidson, re: need water for his blast furnace) (1856 July 12, ALS W. W. to Davidson, re: Grigsby's letter) (1858 Mar. 4, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: general business affairs) (1858 Aug. 4, ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: general business affairs) (1859 Feb. 29, ALS, Henry McCormick to Davidson, re: visit to W. W.) (1859 May 12, ALS, to [W. W.], re: friendly letter) (1859 June 28, ALS, to [W. W.], re: general business news) (1859 Aug. 2, ALS, to [W. W.], re: account of a misdemeanor) (1859 Aug. 5, ALS, D. E. C. Brady to Davidson, re: Will's absence) (1861 Dec. 5, ALS, to W. W., re: travel itinery) (1862 Feb. 4, ALS, to W. W., re: legal affairs re some property) (n.d., ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: copy of notice served to T. Jordan in 1849 folder) (n.d., ALS, W. W. to Davidson, re: deeds, business) (In non correspondence)
Davidson, [Lewis] C. (In non correspondence)
Davidson, S. S. (1862, Mar. 15, ALS, to W. W., re: iron axles)
Davis, Abraham W. (1828 Dec. 31, ALS, Jn. Doyle to Davis, re: shortage of food for hands) (1830 Aug. 23, ALS, Jas. Campbell to Davis, re: delivery of iron from Lexington to Richmond and Charlottesville) (1831 Jan. 19, ALS, to W. W., re: iron) (1831 Mar. 2, ALS, Wm. Jas. Mathews to Davis, re: order of horse shoe iron and mold boards) (1831 Mar. 17, ALS, Jos. Watts to Davis, re: bacon purchase) (1831 Apr. 19, ALS, Jn. W. Schoolfield to Davis, re: light weight iron order) (1831 May 14, ALS, Jordan, Davis & Co. to Davis, re: transportation of additional metal) (1831 May 15, ALS, J., D. & Co. to Davis, re: metal order) (1831 June 17, ALS, J., D. & Co. to Davis, re: coffee) (1831 June 28, ALS, J., D. & Co. to Davis, re: wind mill) (1831 June 29, ALS, J., D. & Co. to Davis, re: load of corn) (1831 July 15, ALS, J. D. & Co. to Davis, re: coal) (In non correspondence)
Davis, Elisha (In non correspondence -receipt)
Davis, E. N. (1855 Jan. 31, ALS, J.D. Davidson to Davis, re: Greenlee estate)
Davis, George D. (l859 Jan., ALS, to W. W., re: iron order)
Davis, Henry (1829 Feb., ALS, to W. W., re: plough moulds) (1829 Apr. 9, ALS, to W. W., re. receipt of load bar) (1829 July 16, ALS, to W. W., re: order for castings)
Dawson, George W. (1862 Jan. 16, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1862 Feb. 4, ALS, to [W. W.], re Geo. Jordan, War news) (1862 Feb. 12, ALS, to W. W., re: inquiry into letter not answered for iron) (1862 Mar. 25, ALS, to W. W., re: Dawson's bill) (1862 Apr. 12, ALS, to W. W., re: request for an additional ton of iron) (1862 May 22, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1862 May 30, ALS, to W. W., re: payment for iron) (1862 Aug. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: inquiry into undelivered iron) (1862 Aug. 18, ALS, to W. W., re: inquiry into undelivered iron) (1862 Oct. 29, ALS, to W. W., re: additional iron wanted) (1862 Nov. 12, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order with payment) (1862 Dec. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order)
Deane (F. B. Jr.) and Son, Lynchburg, Va. (1850 Jan. 13, ALS, to W. W., re: balance of W. W.'s acct.) (1859 Feb. 3, ALS, to W. W., re: demand of payment of acct.) (1859 Mar. 28, ALS, to W. W., re: 30 tons of white pig iron) (1859 Apr. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: cost of said iron) (1859 Apr. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1859 May 17, ALS, to W. W., re: note for $1500) (1859 May 25, ALS, to W. W, re: 20 tons of pig iron) (1859 May 30, ALS, to W. W., re: purchase of scrap iron) (1859 June 15, ALS, to W. W., re: price of iron) (1859 June 20, ALS, to Brady, re: iron order) (1859 July 1, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1859 July 6, ALS, to W. W., re: statement of pig iron delivered) (1859 Sept. 9, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1859 Oct. 13, ALS, to W. W., re: purchase of pipe by the city of Richmond) (1859 Oct. 24, ALS, to W. W., re: gas pipe contract) (1861 Jan. 5, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order requested) (1861 Jan. 10, ALS, to W. W., re: undelivered iron order) (1861 May 9, ALS, to W. W., re: order for new iron) (1861 May 27, ALS, to W. W., re: price of pig iron) (1861 June 4, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1861 June 15, ALS, to W. W., re: incredibly high prices of Weaver's iron) (1861 Aug. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: iron) (1861 Nov. 5, ALS, to W. W., re: inability to procure a boat for iron delivery) (1861 Dec. 1, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1862 Feb. 7, ALS, to W. W., re: receipt of iron)
DeBow, S. H. (1859 June 24, ALS, to W. W., re: Richmond coal field) (1859 July 11, ALS, to W. W., re: unidentified deal) (1859 July 26, ALS, to W. W., re: visit of W. Paumley)
[Deveaux] N. (In non correspondence)
Dickerson, James C. (1829 Jan. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: hired hand) (1830 Oct. 21, ALS, to W. W., re: death of mother of J. C. D.)
Dickinson, Festus (1829 Feb. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: dispute between the two gentlemen over the value of a slave)
Dickinson, Roscoe (1830 Aug. 30, ALS, to W. W., re: bond of W. W.)
Dickinson, Willis E. (1829 Mar. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: the hire or purchace of a cook)
Dillard, William L. (1859 May 26, ALS, to W. W., re: sale of hay) (1859 June 2, ALS, to W. W., re: request for payment of load of hay)
Dixon, T. (In non correspondence)
Donald, William A. (1859 July 19 ALS, to W. W., re: set of wagon tires, one inch thick and two inches wide) (1859 July 22, ALS, to W. W., re: drawing of special tire)
Donihoo, John (1829 Apr. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: sale of five bushels of rye)
Dorman, (W. C. &; G.), Richmond, Va. (1861 May 27, ALS, to W. W., re: payment of bill for belting)
Dorman and Davidson, Lexington (1840 May, ALS, Montyoung & Irvine to Dorman, re: renewal of law suit) (1841 May 14, ALS, Warner Jones to Dorman, re: law suit of Mrs. Ellen Maybury)
[Dougly], Alfred (In non correspondence -legal)
Doyle, John (1828 Feb. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: order of bellows) (1828 Feb. 16, ALS, to W. W., re: order of nails) (1828 Apr. 26, ALS, to W. W., re: order for nails) (1828 Dec. 31, ALS, to A. W. Davis, re: castings now ordered) (1849 Nov. 1, ALS, to J. D. Davidson, re: operation of furnace)
Dudley, Peter (1835 Jan. 10, ALS, to W. W., re: order of bar iron)
Dugless ([Douglas]), Alfred (1857 July 17, ALS, F. T. Anderson to Dugless, re: economic and legal affairs)
Echard, William K. (1859 July 15, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1859 Aug. 5, ALS, to W. W., re: buggy tires)
Echols, John, 1823-1896 (1859 July 5, ALS, to Mr. D[ ], re: executor of Sarah Camthen)
Edmondson, Mr. (In non correspondence)
Ellis, Robert (In non correspondence)
Enteminger, Lewis (In non correspondence -receipts)
Eskridge, George (1829 Jan. 23, ALS, to W. W., re: securities given by Mayburry for the forthcoming of "negroes")
Etna Furnace Metal Co. and Machine Shop (In non correspondence -receipts)
Evans, Washington (1829 Feb. 11, ALS, to W. W., re: note due for collection)
Ewing, J. D. (1859 Mar. 14, ALS, to W. W., re: purchase of 200 lbs. of iron)
[Feince], William (In non correspondence)
Ferguson, Thomas (In non correspondence -receipt)
Finley, (John T.) and Co. (1837 Mar. 15, ALS, to A. W. Davis, re: mould board) (ln non correspondence -notes, 1831)
Fisher, Charles F. (1830 June 22, ALS, to W. W., re: letter to Jacob Strangler)
Flaherty, E. G. (1859 May 9, ALS, to W. W., re: shaft)
Fox, G. R. (1859 Feb. 24, ALS, to [S. V. Rex], re: getting money from W. W.)
Franklin, Albert (1829 June 24, ALS, to W. W., re: request for bacon)
Frick, Jacob (1829 July 18, ALS, to W. W., re: collection of a debt)
Furr, William M (In non correspondence -receipt)
Gales and Seaton, Washington D.C. (In non correspondence)
Gardner Andrew J. (In non correspondence)
Gibson, John (1862 Mar. 15, ALS, to W. W., re: grass seed)
Gilbert, E. H. B. (In non correspondence)
Godwin, Thomas G. (1859 Aug. 22, ALS, to W. W., re: ton of iron) (1859 Sept. 26, ALS, to W. W., re: purchase of iron on condition) (1859 Oct. 11, ALS, to W. W., re: order and payment for one ton of iron) (1859 Oct. 17, ALS, to W. W., re: payment of balance on debt owed) (1861 May 30, ALS, to W. W., re: order for better iron) (1861 July 12, ALS, to W. W., re: payment for order of iron) (1862 Jan. 14, ALS, to W. W., re: request to add additional iron to order) (1862 Jan. 21, ALS, to W. W., re: ton of unworked iron) (1862 Jan. 27, ALS, to W. W., re: iron order) (1862 Feb. 21, ALS, to W. W., re: payment of debt)
Gorgas, Charles K. (1859 Feb. 3, ALS, to uncle W. W., re: general news of business) (1859 Feb. 8, ALS, to W. W., re: statement of expenses of store) (1859 Feb. 20, ALS, to W. W., re: general business) (1859 Mar. 22, ALS, to W. W., re: business and corn) (]859 Mar. 24, ALS, to W. W., re: Reed's wood) (1859 Mar. 28, ALS, to W. W., re: inadequacy of transport to haul iron) (1859 Mar. 29, ALS, Etna, to W.W., re: spoilage of meat) (1859 Mar. 29, ALS, to W. W., re: articles sent for mill, and notice of corn underweight) (1859 Apr. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: weekly corn consumption orders for misc. goods) (l859 April 6, ALS, Etna, to W.W. re: meat) (1859 Apr. 11, ALS, to W. W., re: general business) (1859 Apr. 28, ALS, to W. W., re: information on bookkeeping and accts.) (1859 May 6, ALS, to W. W., re: note on delivery and request for corn) (1859 May 10, ALS, to Brady, re: castings) (1859 May 14, ALS, to W. W., re: general business) (1859 May 17, ALS, to Brady, re: stock & die) (1859 May 24, ALS, to W. W., re: general business) (1859 May 24, ALS, to Brady, re: credit) (1859 May 26, ALS, to Brady, re: shovel molds) (1859 May 29, ALS, to W. W., re: arrival of corn) (1859 June 2 ALS, to W. W., re: supply of corn) (1859 June 4, ALS, to W. W., re: acct. of how corn was used) (1859 June 7, ALS, to W. W., re: feed supply) (1859 June 28, ALS, to W. W., re: general acct. of work to be done) (1859 June 30, ALS, to W. W., re: request for certain articles, e.g. salt and woodfile) (1859 July 8, ALS, to W. W., re iron order; notice that no cattle are for sale) (1859 July 27, ALS, to W. W., re: desire for bacon; mules) (1859 Aug. 4, ALS, to W. W., re: workings of the Etna furnace) (1859 Aug. 6, ALS, to Brady, re: delivery of castings, furnace operation, etc.) (1859 Aug. 9, ALS, to W. W., re: report of iron made) (1859 Aug. 11, ALS, to Brady, re: metal delivery) (1859 Aug. 13, ALS, to W. W., re: management of the forge) (1859 Aug. 16, ALS, to W. W., re: supply of feed and payment of Sam) (1859 Aug. 16, ALS, to B[rady], re: crow bars) (1859 Aug. 23, ALS, to [W. W.], re: request for bacon) (1859 Aug. 25, ALS, to [W. W.], re: old ore metal) (1859 Aug. 30, ALS, to [W. W.], re: general conditions at the forge) (1859 Sept. 9, ALS, to [W. W.], re: report of conditions at the forge) (1859 Sept. 15, ALS, to W. W., re report of conditions at the forge) (1859 Sept. 22, ALS, to W. W., re: furnace is idle) (1859 Sept. 27, ALS, to W. W., re: scrap iron) (1859 Sept. 29, ALS, to W. W., re: furnace pinion) (1859 Nov. 5, ALS, to Brady, re: report of crops in and affairs in general) (1859 Nov. 10, ALS, to Brady, re: request for supplies and report of affairs at the furnace) (1859 Nov. 12, ALS to Brady, re: containers for oil and price of hides) (1859 Nov. 15, ALS, to Brady, re: news about the forge) (1859 Nov. 19, ALS, to Brady, re: general business) (1859 Nov. 22, ALS, to Brady, re: return of faulty iron goods) (1859 Nov. 24, ALS, to Brady, re: boots and irons) (1859 Dec. 6, ALS, to W. W., re: general business affairs) (In non correspondence)
Gorgas, P. K. (1829 Feb. 22, ALS, to W. W., re: Conrad's acct. of the business) (1845 Nov. 3, ALS, W. W. to Gorgas, re: Jas. Barclay's land) (1846 July 21, ALS, W. W. to Gorgas, re: payment of bills) (1846 Sept. 21, ALS, W.W. to Gorgas, re. railroad iron) (In non correspondence)
Graham, Arch (1862 Aug. 13, ALS, to Brady, re: iron memo) (1862 Aug. 21, ALS, to Brady, re: offer to pay extra for iron)
Greenlee, H. L. (1861 Aug. 7, ALS, to W. W., re: request for cast ploughs)
Greenlee, James (In non correspondence -legal)
Grigsby Joseph (In non correspondence -receipt)
Grigsby, Reuben (In non correspondence -receipt)
[Grimke], Mrs. Hannah J. (1855 Sept. 1, ALS, to J.D. Davidson, re: sale of slave)
Guggenheim, Fred (1862 Dec. 1, ALS to W. W., re: sale of the Morgan Place)
Guy & Patton (In non correspondence)
[Gwynn], Walter (ln non correspondence)
Hamilton, William (In non correspondence -receipts)
Hardy, Wesley (1859 May 26, ALS, to W. W., re: 100 lbs. 3/4 iron) (In non correspondence -receipt)
Hart, John B. (In non oorrespondence -receipt)
Hartbrook, M. M. (1859 Jan. 18, ALS, to W. W., re: iron purchase) (1859 Mar. 2, ALS, to W. W., re: iron purchase)